MARKO HENRIK HAUTALA

Fullstack Software Developer

github.com/markohautala / linkedin.com/in/markohautala Stockholm, Sweden / markohautala@live.se / 072-291-07-50



Executive Summary

Hi, I am Marko. I have a +7-year long experience in team-collaboration and communicating with other people and I have fantastic references to prove that where I work I deliver exceptionally good service, great end-results and positive influence on my colleagues. I love coding and amongst my skills are HTML/CSS, React, Django and many more amongst the fullstack range. I have a really good attention to detail, a strong ability to analyze and an ability for quick problem-solving. Also, I am always willing to learn new things and improve myself.

Education

Jun 2023 - Present	Code Institute	Dublin, Ireland (Remote Based Learning)
	Diploma in Fullstack Software Development - Advanced front end with React	
	(Accredited by the University West of Scotland)	
Sept 2016 - Jun 2021	Stockholm University &	Stockholm, Sweden
	The Swedish School of Sport and Health Sciences Physical education (PE) teacher	

Technical Skillset

Client-side	Server-side	Development & operations
HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, jQuery	Python, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Django, Flask, Jinja, MongoDB, JSON	Jest, Agile, CI/CD, Git, GitHub, Heroku, API, DevTools, Figma, VSCode

Portfolio Projects

- 1. **Django Authentication and CRUD Application** A application with full CRUD-functionality and user Authentication. **Tech used:** HTML, CSS, Python, Django framework, JavaScript, SQL-database, Heroku. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/django-auth-crud-app
- 2. **React Application** A to-do application built and based on React. **Tech used:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Heroku. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/react-app
- 3. **Flask Project** A website developed using the Flask framework. **Tech used:** Flask, Python, Jinja, HTML, CSS, JSON. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/Flask-project
- 4. **Bootstrap Online Resume** My own online resume built with Bootstrap. **Tech Used:** HTML, CSS, API, Bootstrap, emailJS, JavaScript. Link: https://markohautala.github.io/bootstrap-online-resume/

Collaborative Projects

Hackathon (agile collaboration) - built a website to calculate investment profitability using NPV. **Tech used:** HTML, CSS, Django, Vercel, Materialize.

https://eu.badgr.com/public/assertions/ZRUiU4O2R52vnJjw8SbO5w?identity_email=markohautala@live.se

Work Experience

Aug. 2021 - Present Fornuddens school (Tyresö Kommun) Physical Education (PE) teacher Tyresö, Stockholm

- **Active Listening and Communication:** I engage in daily communication and collaboration with various school stakeholders, enhancing effective teamwork and understanding of different needs.
- Stress Management and Time Management: I handle teaching responsibilities, administrative tasks, and documentation under tight deadlines, demonstrating excellent stress management and time management skills.
- **Decision Making and Problem Solving:** I lead a team of six colleagues, making quick decisions and solving unexpected issues efficiently, showing strong leadership and critical thinking abilities.
- **Organization and Adaptability:** I initiate and manage projects to improve work routines, displaying organizational skills, multitasking ability, and adaptability to new challenges.

June 2016 - June 2018 Kaffeknappen AB Service & Customer Relations Manager Stockholm, Sweden

- **High responsibility:** Managed exclusive coffee machines for large companies in Södermalm, maintaining high service standards.
- **Problem-solving and adaptability:** I retained Kaffeknappen's largest corporate client by resolving dissatisfaction, earning positive feedback (see reference).
- **Time management and self-motivation:** I showed strong independence, responsibility, and efficiency in meeting deadlines.

Additional Information/Interests

- Listening continuously to the tech podcast "Kodsnack" and "Developers!" to stay updated with the software/IT industry.
- Strong interest and a daily usage of different Al-technologies.
- Regular engagement in coding communities and on Slack tech forum.
- Coding on personal portfolio projects every day.
- High interests in self-improvement, fitness, food and nutrition.
- I both speak and write fluently in Swedish, English and Finnish.

Kaffeknappen AB

"Regarding Marko, I cannot praise him enough. He provides fantastic service and maintains a very professional attitude with customers. He is an incredibly important ambassador for the company Kaffeknappen. It is rare to see such a young man take on such comprehensive responsibility towards customers.

Best regards,

A very satisfied customer (DN - Dagens Nyheter)."

More references available on request.